Guide to the Helen and Newton Harrison Papers M1797
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 5. Performances and Exhibitions, 1961-2014
  - The Unconventional Landscape, John Michael Kohler Arts Center, Sheboygan, WI (April 23 - June 11, 1989), 1989-1990 (Box 143, Folder 5)
  - A Delicate Balance: Technics, Culture and Consequences, California State University, Los Angeles, CA (October 16 - November 14, 1989) (Box 143, Folder 6)
  - Best of the Eighties, Laguna Art Museum, Laguna Beach, CA (November 4, 1989) (Box 143, Folder 7)
  - The End of Weather As We Know It, Randolph Street Gallery, Chicago, IL (November 17- December 22, 1989) (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Diversity & Presence, Traveling exhibition, 1989 (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Ressource Kunst - Die Elemente neu gesehen, Traveling exhibition, 1989 (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Terra Incognita: Contemporary Landscape Painting, Museum of Art at the Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, RI (November 17- December 22, 1989), 1989-1990 (Box 143, Folder 11)
  - Collecting / Organizing / Transposing, Traveling exhibition (March 16, 1990 opening), 1988-1989 (Box 143, Folder 12)
  - Collecting / Organizing / Transposing, Maryland Art Place, Baltimore, MD (March 16, 1990 opening), 1989 (Flat-box 276, Folder 3)
  - Artists and the Environment, The Armory Center for the Arts, Pasadena, CA (April 8 - May 13, 1990) (Box 143, Folder 13)
  - Garbage Out Front: A New Era for Public Design, The Urban Center, New York City, NY (June 7 - September 15, 1990) (Box 143, Folder 14)
  - Polemical Landscapes, Museum of Art at the University of California, Riverside, Riverside, CA (June 10 - July 29, 1990), 1989-1990 (Box 143, Folder 15)
  - Signs of Life: Process and Material, 1960-1990, Institute of Contemporary Art at the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA (June 15 - August 12, 1990) (Box 143, Folder 16)
  - Savoir-Vivre, Savoir-Faire, Savoir Être, Centre International d'Art Contemporain de Montréal, Quebec (September 1 - October 28, 1990) (Box 143, Folder 17)
  - The Invisible Thread: The Tao of Contemporary Art, Hofstra Museum at Hofstra University, Hempstead, NY (October 4 - December 9, 1990), 1989 (Box 143, Folder 18)
  - The Sava River: A New History, Palmer Museum of Art at Pennsylvania State University, University Park, PA (October 8 - November 4, 1990), 1989-1991 (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - The Common Wealth: Twentieth Century American Masterpieces from Virginia Collections, Roanoke Museum of Fine Arts, Roanoke, VA (December 1, 1990 - February 3, 1991), 1990-1991 (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - The Book of the Seven Lagoons, Kunstverein in Hamburg, Hamburg, Germany, 1990 (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - Team Spirit, Traveling exhibition, 1990 (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Artists Contributing to the Solution (A.C.T.S.), The Woman's Building, Los Angeles, CA (January 19 - March 2, 1991), 1989-1991 (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Changing the Conversation, Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, New York City, NY (March 2 - April 6, 1991) (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Consorts, Pence Gallery, Santa Monica, CA (July 13 - August 24, 1991) (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - ARTEC '91, International Biennale in Nagoya, Japan, Correspondence (October 10 - November 17, 1991), 1990-1991, 1993-1994 (Box 144, Folder 8)
  - ARTEC '91, International Biennale in Nagoya, Japan, Correspondence (October 10 - November 17, 1991) [RESTRICTED] (Box 262, Folder 2)
  - ARTEC '91, International Biennale in Nagoya, Japan, Exhibition material (October 10 - November 17, 1991) (Box 144, Folders 9-10)
  - ARTEC '91, International Biennale in Nagoya, Japan, Nagara River (October 10 - November 17, 1991) (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - ARTEC '91, International Biennale in Nagoya, Japan, Exhibition material (October 10 - November 17, 1991) (Flat-box 276, Folder 4)
  - Imperiled Shores, The Baxter Gallery at the Portland School of Art, Portland, ME (January 21 - March 8, 1992), 1991-1992 (Box 144, Folder 12)
  - Changing the Conversation, Environmental Projects Proposed and in Progress, Gallery of Art at Washington University, St. Louis, MO (January 24 - March 22, 1992), 1991-1992 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Domestic Violence, CRCA Gallery at the University of Texas at Arlington, Arlington, TX (February - March, 1992), 1991 (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Book of Seven Lagoons, Frontispiece Gallery at the Minnesota Center for Book Arts, Minneapolis, MN (March 7 - May 23, 1992), 1991-1992 (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - Americas, Monasterio de Santa Clara, Moguer, Huelva, Spain (August 1 - September 1, 1992) (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Differentes Natures, Traveling exhibition, 1992-1994 (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Exploring Maps, Turman Art Gallery at Indiana State University, Terre Haute, IN (March 23 - April 19, 1992) (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Exploring Maps, Turman Art Gallery at Indiana State University, Terre Haute, IN (March 23 - April 19, 1992) (Flat-box 276, Folder 5)
  - Art and Environment, The National Arts Club, New York City, NY (April 21 - May 1, 1993) (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Art and Environment, Art Galleries at Allegheny College, Meadville, PA (September 7 - September 30, 1993) (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - Art-Culture-Ecology (Kunst-Kultur-Ökologie), Bea Voigt Galerie, Munich, Germany (September 10, 1993 opening), 1993-1995 (Box 145, Folder 9)
    Includes conference
  - Art-Culture-Ecology (Kunst-Kultur-Ökologie), Bea Voigt Galerie, Munich, Germany (September 10 - November 30, 1993) (Flat-box 276, Folder 6)
  - San Diego Artists from the Collection of the Museum of Contemporary Art, San Diego, Boehm Gallery at Palomar College, San Marcos, CA (October 15 - November 17, 1993) (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - Serpentine Lattice, Dahl Fine Arts Center, Rapid City, SD, 1993-1994 (Box 145, Folder 11)
  - Earthworks, Fuel Gallery, Seattle, WA (April 7 - May 1, 1994) (Box 145, Folder 12)
  - Public Interventions, The Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston, MA (April 27 - July 17, 1994), 1992-1994 (Box 145, Folder 13)
  - Art on the Map, Chicago Cultural Center, Chicago, IL (April 30 - July 10, 1994) (Box 145, Folder 14)
  - Generation of Mentors, National Museum of Women in the Arts, Washington, DC (June 9 - August 21, 1994) (Box 145, Folder 15)
  - Breathing Space for the Sava River, Performance at Laguna Art Museum, Laguna Beach, CA (August 17, 1994) (Box 145, Folder 16)
  - Effect or Infect, Soho 20 Gallery, New York City, NY (September 27 - October 22, 1994) (Box 145, Folder 17)
  - Creative Solutions to Ecological Issues, Traveling exhibition, 1994 (Box 145, Folder 18)
  - Second Nature: Contemporary Representations of the Natural World, American Museum of Natural History, New York City, NY, 1994 (Box 145, Folder 19)
  - Soma Gallery, San Diego, CA, 1994 (Box 145, Folder 20)
  - Facing Eden: 100 Years of Landscape Art in the Bay Area, M. H. de Young Memorial Museum, San Francisco, CA (June 24 - September 10, 1995), 1993-1994 (Box 145, Folder 21)
  - The Edge of Town, Joseloff Gallery at the University of Hartford, West Hartford, CT (November 9, 1995 - January 15,1996), 1993-1995 (Box 146, Folders 1-3)
  - The Edge of Town, Joseloff Gallery at the University of Hartford, West Hartford, CT (November 9, 1995 - January 15, 1996) (Map-folder 463)
  - Hannover 2000 installation proposals for The Many Futures for Greenhouse Europe and Fort the Glass House in Hannover: A Rain Forest Ensemble, Hannover, Germany, 1996 (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - As Far as the Eye Can See, Atlanta College of Art Gallery, Atlanta, GA (January 29 - March 7, 1999) (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - Natural Reality: Artistic Positions between Nature and Consent, Ludwig Forum and city of Aachen, Germany (June 25 - October 3, 1999), 1998 (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Picturing California's Other Landscape: The Great Central Valley, Haggin Museum, Stockton, CA (October 17 - December 31, 1999), 1999-2000 (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - The Serpentine Lattice, Clara Hatton Gallery at Colorado State University, Fort Collins, CO (January 31 - March 3, 2000), 1999-2000 (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Made in California: Art, Image, and Identity, 1900-2000, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Los Angeles, CA (October 22 - February 25, 2001), 1999-2001 (Box 146, Folder 9)
  - I-5 California: Four Decades of Contemporary Art, San Diego Museum of Art, San Diego, CA (April 2001 opening) (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Making Nature, Edsvik Art, Stockholm, Sweden, 2001 (Box 146, Folder 11)
  - Ecovention: Current Art to Transform Ecologies, The Contemporary Arts Center, Cincinnati, OH (June 22 - August 18, 2002), 2001-2002 (Box 146, Folder 12)
  - Art / Women / California 1950-2000: Parallels and Intersections, San Jose Museum of Art, San Jose, CA (July 13 - November 3, 2002), 1999-2002 (Box 146, Folder 13)
  - Flow Lines, Pasadena City College Art Gallery, Pasadena, CA (October 2002) (Box 146, Folder 14)
  - Peninsula Europe, Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, New York City, NY, Installation notes (April 12 - May 10, 2003) (Box 146, Folder 15)
  - Peninsula Europe, Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, New York City, NY, Love-notes and correspondence (April 12 - May 10, 2003) (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Peninsula Europe, Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, New York City, NY, Mailing lists (April 12 - May 10, 2003) (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Imaging the River, Hudson River Museum, Yonkers, NY (October 4, 2003 - May 23, 2004), 2003-2004 (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Public Art: Artist's Proposals, Bowman, Penelc and Megahan Art Galleries at Allegheny College, Meadville, PA (January 20 - February 11, 2004), 2003-2004 (Box 147, Folder 4)
  - Survival Aesthetics, Gut Friedrichstein, Sankt Augustin, Germany, 2004 (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Landscape: Theme and Variations, Schneider Museum of Art at Southern Oregon University Ashland, OR (September 30 - December 10, 2005) (Box 147, Folder 6)
    Item removed to be housed with computer media / born-digital material. Box 264 Item #: M1797_CM 344 Title: Schneider Museum; Gallery Photos Format: CD
  - Groundworks: Environmental Collaboration in Contemporary Art, Regina Gouger Miller Gallery, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA (November - December, 2005) (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Visual Politics: Art of Engagement, Traveling exhibition, 2005-2006 (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - L.A. River Reborn, Skirball Cultural Center, Los Angeles, CA (April 6 - September 3, 2006), 2005-2006 (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Envisioning Change: Melting Ice - A Hot Topic?, Traveling exhibition, 2006-2008 (Box 147, Folder 10)
  - Called to Action: Environmental Restoration by Artists, Art Sites, Riverhead NY (May 5 - June 3, 2007), 2006-2007 (Box 147, Folder 11)
  - Weather Report: Art and Climate Change, Boulder Museum of Contemporary Art, Boulder, CO (September 14 - December 21, 2007) (Box 147, Folder 12)
  - Global Warming, Ronald Feldman Gallery Fine Arts, New York City, NY (January 10 - February 7, 2009) (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - San Diego and the Origins of Conceptual Art in California, Cardwell Jimmerson Contemporary Art, Culver City, CA (February 24 - April 2009) (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Vertical Gardens, Exit Art Gallery, New York City, NY (March 25 - May 23, 2009) (Box 148, Folder 3)
  - Radical Nature - Art and Architecture for a Changing Planet 1969-2009, Barbican Art Gallery, London, England (June 19 - September 20, 2009), 2008-2009 (Box 148, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition reviews, 2009 (Box 148, Folder 5)
  - Landscapes as an Idea. Projects and Projections: 1960-1980, KM Kulturunea, Donostia-San Sebastián, Spain (June 10 - September 25, 2010) (Box 148, Folder 6)
  - Artpark, A Ten Year Survey, 1974-1984, University at Buffalo Art Gallery, Buffalo, NY (Fall 2010), 2006-2008 (Box 148, Folder 7)
  - Paris Prix Coal 2014, La Muśee de la Chasse et de la Nature, Paris, France (July 10, 2013 - April 18, 2014), 2013-2014 (Flat-box 276, Folders 7-12, Flat-box 277, Folders 1-2)
  - EcoVisionaries, Ecological Art: Designs for Living on Earth, undated (Box 148, Folder 8)
  - Performance notes, Berkeley performance, undated (Box 148, Folder 9)
  - Performance notes, Misc., undated (Box 148, Folder 10)
  - Performance notes, Talking Water, undated (Box 148, Folder 11)
  - Performance scripts, Baltimore Promenade, undated (Box 148, Folder 12)
  - Performance scripts, Great Lakes Meditation, undated (Box 148, Folder 13)
  - Performance scripts, Sacramento Meditations, undated (Box 148, Folder 14)
  - Performance scripts, Talking Water, undated (Box 148, Folder 15)
  - Performance scripts, Talking Waters, undated (Box 148, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified exhibition, undated (Map-tube MT #26)
    Mostly likely at the KAH in Bonn, Germany. Includes two large pieces of paper with the exhibition space area and three pieces of tissue paper with pencil sketches of the exhibition layout. The following information is found on the tissues paper pencil sketches: Tibet, Great Lakes, Einzugsgebeit, Pacific Northwest, Holland, Hot Winds and Warm Rains, Sava, Compassion, Crab Farm, Wall Piece. Once piece of tissue paper is taped to one of the larger pieces of paper.
    Could be linked to the rooftop garden for Future Garden at the KAH; small tear at the end of one of the larger pieces of paper.
  - Unidentified exhibitions, undated (Box 148, Folder 17)
- Series 6. Presentations and Speeches, 1970-2010
  This series documents the Harrisons awards and honors, interviews and profiles, lectures, workshops, conferences, and panels they participated in throughout their career. It includes correspondence, contracts and agreements, flyers, mailers, posters, awards, interview transcripts, and lecture notes. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries 1. Awards and honors, 1970-2010
    This subseries consists of awards and honors received by Helen Mayer Harrison, Newtown Harrison, and the Harrisons collectively. It includes material documenting Helen’s Vesta Award (1989), the Silver Apple Award for Alternating Discourse: The Works of Helen and Newton Harrison (1990), and the Chartered Institution of Water and Environmental Management’s (CIWEM) Nick Reeves Award for Arts and the Environment (2010). It houses correspondence, publicity, and certificates. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Awards and honors; Outstanding Educators of America, 1970, 1972 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Awards and honors; Pacific Institute of Creativity, 1971 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Awards and honors; Who's Who in American Art, 1972, 1978-1982, undated (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Awards and honors; Who's Who in America, 1977-1979 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Awards and honors; Honorary Herpetologists from the Largesse Foundation, 1978 (Box 149, Folder 5)
    - Awards and honors; Contemporary Artists, 1982, undated (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Awards and honors; Dictionary of International Biography, 1984 (Box 149, Folder 7)
    - Awards and honors; The New York Art Review, 1989 (Box 149, Folder 8)
    - Awards and honors; Vesta Award, 1989 (Box 149, Folder 9)
    - Awards and honors; American Artists, 1990 (Box 149, Folder 10)
    - Awards and honors; Silver Apple Award at the 1990 Educational Film and Video Festival for Altering Discourse: The Works of Helen and Newton Harrison (Box 149, Folder 11)
    - Awards and honors; Internationaler Preis für ökologisch wegweisendes Bauen und Städteplanen in Ostdeutschland, 2nd pries für Bitterfeld Braunkohlebrachen, 1993 (Box 149, Folder 12)
    - Awards and honors; Chrysler Award for Innovation in Design nomination, 1994 (Box 149, Folder 13)
    - Awards and honors; Who's Who in Fine Arts Higher Education, 2003 (Box 149, Folder 14)
    - Awards and honors; CIWEM (The Chartered Institution of Water and Environmental Management) Arts and Environment Award, 2010 (Box 149, Folder 15)
    - Awards and honors; American Biographical Institute, undated (Box 149, Folder 16)
    - Awards and honors; Buckminster Fuller prize for Tibet is the High Ground III, undated (Box 149, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2. Interviews and profiles, 1970-2010
    This subseries consists of the Harrisons’ interviews and profiles. It houses correspondence, transcripts, and article drafts of various interviews and profiles, including transcripts for interviews with Gail Scott (1970), Dick Higgins (1978), Michael Auping (1982), Craig Adcock (1991), Reiko Goto (2008), Brandon Ballengée (2009) and Peter Selz (2010). This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Interviews and profiles; Interview: Gail Scott and Newton Harrison, 1970 (Box 149, Folder 18)
    - Interviews and profiles; Unidentified interview transcript, circa 1970-1975 (Box 149, Folder 19)
    - Interviews and profiles; Newton and Helen Harrison interview with Dick Higgins, 1978 (Box 149, Folder 20)
    - Interviews and profiles; Video Data Bank at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago, 1978, 1980-1982 (Box 149, Folder 21)
    - Interviews and profiles; "A Morning Conversation with the Harrisons" transcript, 1979 (Box 149, Folder 22)
      by Tom Huston
    - Interviews and profiles; Harrisons interviewed by Vicki Linder for Omni magazine, 1981 (Box 149, Folder 23)
    - Interviews and profiles; Helen and Newton Harrison, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 24)
      by Michael Auping
    - Interviews and profiles; An Interview with Helen and Newton Harrison with Michael Auping, 1982 (Box 149, Folder 25)
    - Interviews and Profiles; "Nobody Told Us When to Stop Thinking: An Interview with the Harrisons," The Quarterly Bulletin of the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center, N.S. Vol. 1 #2, Spring 1987 (Flat-box 279, Folder 14)
    - Interviews and profiles; Newton and Helen Harrison: Lagoon cycle, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Interviews and profiles; San Diego Artists book, 1988 (Box 150, Folder 2)
    - Interviews and profiles; Channel 17, San Diego, CA, 1990 (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Interviews and profiles; Helen Mayer and Newton Harrison: Working in Pasadena, 1990 (Box 150, Folder 4)
      by Jay Belloli
    - Interviews and profiles; Intervju: Newton Harrison and Helen Mayer Harrison in M'ARS, 1990 (Box 150, Folder 5)
    - Interviews and profiles; Conversational Drift: Helen Mayer Harrison and Newton Harrison, 1991 (Box 150, Folder 6)
      by Craig Adcock
    - Interviews and profiles; "Newton Harrison Discusses Josef Albers: A Conversation with Fred Horowitz, December 3, 1996" transcript (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Interviews and profiles; V-Style magazine, 1997 (Box 150, Folder 8)
    - Interviews and profiles; The Public Art Journal interview by Davina Thackery, 1999-2000 (Box 150, Folder 9)
    - Interviews and profiles; Grant Kester's book, 2005-2007 (Box 150, Folder 10)
    - Interviews and profiles; Questions from JenJoy, circa 2005-2010 (Box 150, Folder 11)
    - Interviews and profiles; James Sidaway, 2007 (Box 150, Folder 12)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Helen Mayer Harrison and Newton Harrison, Interviewed by Reiko Goto, 8 March 2008, Novotel Hotel, Bristol, Part 1 and Part 2" transcript (Box 150, Folder 13)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Erika Yarrow talks to artists Helen and Newton Harrison about their new exhibition 'Greenhouse Britain: Losing Ground, Gaining Wisdom'", 2008 (Box 150, Folder 14)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Eden 3: Ethical and Aesthetic Impulse Conversation, 19 September 2008" transcript (Box 150, Folder 15)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Helen and Newton Harrison conversation with Brandon Ballengée, 14 January 2009, conducted at Ronald Feldman Gallery, New York, NY on the Occasion of the Harrisons' solo exhibition 'Global Warming'" transcript (Box 150, Folder 16)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Helen Mayer Harrison and Newton Harrison with Peter Selz" transcript, 2010 (Box 150, Folder 17)
    - Interviews and profiles; "Debat 1 Oktober Kasteel Groeneveld" transcript, undated (Box 150, Folder 18)
    - Interviews and profiles; "On Commissions", undated (Box 150, Folder 19)
    - Interviews and profiles; Videotape interviews produced by Andy Eason and Gerry Rosen on Contemporary Artists / West Coast, undated (Box 150, Folder 20)
    - Interviews and profiles; Unidentified, undated (Box 150, Folder 21)
    - Interviews and profiles; Unidentified interview in The Atlanta Art Workers Coalition Newspaper, undated (Box 150, Folder 22)
  - Subseries 3. Presentations, 1970-2010
    This subseries consists of correspondence, mailers, flyers, posters, programs, lecture transcripts, and notes documenting numerous workshops, lectures, panels, programs, forums, and conferences that the Harrisons participated in throughout their careers. This subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Invitational Conference in Advanced Placement in Art and Music (June 11-13, 1970) (Box 150, Folder 23)
    - Reader for the feasibility tests in art, Colorado Springs, CO (September 9-10, 1970) (Box 150, Folder 24)
    - Mandala Series, Presentation at The Junior Arts Center, Los Angeles, CA (April 22, 1972) (Box 150, Folder 25)
    - College Art Association Annual Meeting, New York City, NY (January 24-27, 1973), 1972-1973 (Box 150, Folder 26)
    - "The Butcher, The Baker, The Candlestick Maker: The Contemporary Artist as Everything Else," Program at the University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA (February 3, 1975), 1974 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - "Visuals and Voices: The Natural and the Synthesized," Symposium at the Center for Music Experimentation, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA (February 11-22, 1974) (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - "Validating Modern Art: The Impact of Museums upon Modern Art History," Symposium, Los Angeles, CA (June 24, 1975) (Box 151, Folder 3)
    - "Art and Artists: New Directions," Program at Palomar College, San Marcos, CA (March 8, 1976), 1975 (Box 151, Folder 4)
    - "Art and Artists: New Directions 4," Lecture series at Palomar College, San Marcos, CA (March 8, 1976) (Map-folder 464)
    - The Orange Unified School District Drawing Seminar for Art I, Presentation at Chapman College, Orange, CA (March 23, 1976), 1975 (Box 151, Folder 5)
    - Art Medallion Show, Helen Mayer Harrison is a juror, Villa Park, CA (May 3, 1976) (Box 151, Folder 6)
    - Visiting artists at Hartford Art School at the University of Hartford, West Hartford, CT (October 12, 1976) (Box 151, Folder 7)
    - "Friends of Modern Art Lecture Series," Lecture at the Detroit Institute of Arts, Detroit, MI (October 13, 1976) (Box 151, Folder 8)
    - "Friends of Modern Art Lecture Series," Lecture at the Detroit Institute of Arts, Detroit, MI (October 13, 1976) (Flat-box 279, Folder 15)
    - College Art Association Annual Meeting, Los Angeles, CA (February 1-5, 1977) (Box 151, Folder 9)
    - "CONNECTIONS ... Planetary... Personal... Political," Conference at the Bonaventure, Los Angeles, CA (May 27-30, 1977) (Box 151, Folder 10)
    - Visiting artists at the San Francisco Art Institute, Lecture to the Waterfront class, San Francisco, CA (October 28 and November 8, 1977), 1977-1978 (Box 151, Folder 11)
    - "Artist Talk with Scientists," Conference at the Otis Arts Institute of Los Angeles, CA, 1977-1978 (Box 151, Folder 12)
    - LAICA Journal, Contribution to "Notes on a Recent Project", 1977 (Box 151, Folder 13)
    - Visit to Claremont Graduate School, Claremont, CA, 1977 (Box 151, Folder 14)
    - Visiting Artists Program at the San Francisco Art Institute, San Francisco, CA, 1977 (Box 151, Folder 15)
    - "The Gentle Art of Survival: Alternative Technologies," Series coordinated by the Center for Twentieth Century Studies at the University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee, Milwaukee, WI (April 27, 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 151, Folder 16)
    - "The Gentle Art of Survival: Alternative Technologies," Series coordinated by the Center for Twentieth Century Studies at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee, Milwaukee, WI (April 27, 1978) [RESTRICTED] (Box 262, Folder 3)
    - Lecture at the Living University at San Diego State University, San Diego, CA (June 14, 1978) (Box 151, Folder 17)